(yue)粵文字幕:
www.cantocaptions.com
(en)Cantonese subtitles:
(yue)（遙遠嘅大陸北方盡頭）
(en)(The northern end of the distant continent)
(yue)（我抵達咗被世人稱為天國嘅地方）
(en)(I arrived at the place that people call heaven)
(yue)（"靈魂長眠之地"）
(en)("The place where souls rest eternally")
(yue)（嗰度係個聚集咗好多靈魂嘅地方）
(en)(That place gathered many souls)
(yue)（我同過去嘅戰友對話）
(en)(I spoke with my former comrades)
(yue)（大魔法使弗蘭梅）
(en)(The great magician Flamme)
(yue)芙莉蓮
(en)Frieren
(yue)已經可以見到皇都喇
(en)We can already see the royal capital
(yue)我哋幾個同勇者一齊凱旋而歸
(en)We're all returning triumphantly with the hero
(yue)全國上下而家一定好興奮
(en)The whole country must be very excited now
(yue)返到去之後，就要開始揾嘢做喇
(en)After we get back, we'll need to start finding something to do
(yue)乜你已經開始考慮緊呢樣嘢嗱？
(en)Are you already thinking about that?
(yue)呢樣嘢好緊要㗎
(en)This is very important
(yue)就算我哋已經打贏咗魔王都要繼續生活
(en)Even though we've defeated the demon king, we still need to continue living
(yue)之後落嚟嘅人生仲有好長㗎
(en)The rest of our lives are still very long
(yue)要揾嘢做
(en)Need to find something to do
(yue)如果份工可以隨時飲酒就好喇
(en)It would be great if the job allows drinking anytime
(yue)你唔係僧侶嚟咩？
(en)Aren't you a priest?
(yue)噉講又係𠸏
(en)I guess you're right
(yue)芙莉蓮，你跟住落嚟嘅人生
(en)Frieren, your life from now on
(yue)一定會比我哋可以想象得到嘅
(en)Will definitely be much longer than what we can imagine
(yue)更加漫長得多啊嗬？
(en)Much longer, right?
(yue)我諗應該係喇
(en)I think so
(yue)《葬送的芙莉蓮》
(en)Frieren: Beyond Journey's End
(yue)勇者欣梅爾
(en)Hero Himmel
(yue)戰士艾冉
(en)Warrior Eisen
(yue)僧侶海塔
(en)Priest Heiter
(yue)魔法使芙莉蓮
(en)Mage Frieren
(yue)你哋今次成功打敗咗魔王做得好好
(en)You all have done well defeating the demon king this time
(yue)從此，世界將會迎嚟和平嘅時代
(en)From now on, the world will enter an era of peace
(yue)聽講國王陛下
會整我哋嘅雕像放喺廣場嗰度啊
(en)I heard His Majesty will make statues of us and place them in the square
(yue)不過，個雕像究竟可唔可以真實還原到
我呢個咁俊俏不凡嘅樣呢？
(en)However, can the statue truly capture my handsome and extraordinary appearance?
(yue)講真我好有保留囖
(en)Honestly, I have my reservations
(yue)佢哋班人真係現實
(en)These people are really pragmatic
(yue)開始旅程嗰陣
明明只係畀咗十個銅幣我哋咋
(en)When we started the journey, they only gave us ten copper coins
(yue)好喇，算數啦，芙莉蓮
(en)Alright, let's call it even, Frieren
(yue)橫掂而家可以噉樣免費任飲酒
(en)Anyway, now we can drink all we want for free
(yue)噉樣已經夠啦，係咪啊？
(en)That's enough, isn't it?
(yue)你個酒肉和尚
(en)You booze-loving monk
(yue)旅程已經完結喇
(en)The journey is already over
(yue)講得啱啊
(en)That's right
(yue)我哋嘅冒險到呢度終於都完喇
(en)Our adventure has finally ended here
(yue)已經十年喇
(en)It's been ten years
(yue)喺呢段時間發生咗好多事
(en)A lot has happened during this time
(yue)我記得出發嗰一日
(en)I remember the day we departed
(yue)欣梅爾同艾冉對國王陛下不敬
(en)Himmel and Eisen were disrespectful to His Majesty
(yue)爭啲被處死
(en)They were almost executed
(yue)一唔小心我哋嘅冒險可能會喺嗰度完
(en)If we weren't careful, our adventure might have ended there
(yue)郁手
(en)Move
(yue)海塔仲試過因為宿醉一啲用都冇
(en)Heiter was once completely useless because of a hangover
(yue)連路都行唔到啊
(en)He couldn't even walk
(yue)你塊面青到好似不死族噉喎，冇嘢吖嘛？
(en)Your face is as pale as an undead. Are you okay?
(yue)-唔得喇
-都估到你㗎喇
(en)-I can't take it anymore
-I figured as much
(yue)佢每個禮拜都會有一次醉到噉
(en)He gets this drunk once every week
(yue)喺呢方面嘅話，我就好優秀
(en)In this regard, I'm very excellent
(yue)-你爭啲畀寶箱怪食咗嗰陣
-好黑啊，好得人驚啊
(en)-When you were almost eaten by a mimic
-It's so dark, it's terrifying
(yue)我哋有諗過抌低你㗎
(en)We thought about abandoning you
(yue)-同你講咗好多次係陷阱啦，仲中招
-你哋唔好企喺度快啲過嚟幫下我啦，好驚
(en)-Told you many times it's a trap, yet you still fell for it
-Don't just stand there, come help me, I'm scared
(yue)-蠢成咁不如抌低佢喇
-唔好，唔好食我啊
(en)-He's so stupid, let's just leave him
-No, don't eat me
(yue)真係吖
(en)Really
(yue)淨係諗到啲搞笑嘅回憶啊
(en)I can only think of funny memories
(yue)不過真係好開心啊
(en)But it was really fun
(yue)我好慶幸可以同你哋一齊冒險係真㗎
(en)I'm truly grateful to have adventured with you all
(yue)冇錯，講得啱啊
(en)Yes, that's right
(yue)雖然呢段冒險嘅時間有啲短
(en)Although this adventure was a bit short
(yue)你話有啲短？你喺度講咩啊？
(en)A bit short? What are you talking about?
(yue)成十年喎
(en)It was ten whole years
(yue)你睇下海塔，已經由後生仔變咗做大叔喇
(en)Look at Heiter, he's gone from a young man to an old guy
(yue)你噉講嘢㗎？
(en)Is that how you talk?
(yue)佢本來就係大叔
(en)He was always an old guy
(yue)連你都噉講？
(en)Even you say that?
(yue)差唔多要開始喇
(en)It's about to begin
(yue)好似係叫半世紀流星，係咪啊？
(en)It's called the half-century meteor, isn't it?
(yue)50年先會出現一次嘅流星雨
(en)A meteor shower that appears only once every 50 years
(yue)好啱用嚟做揭開呢個和平時代嘅序幕啊
(en)Perfect for marking the beginning of this era of peace
(yue)真係好靚啊
(en)It's really beautiful
(yue)喺呢個城鎮好難睇得清啊
(en)It's hard to see clearly in this town
(yue)我而家喺度感動緊㗎
(en)I'm feeling moved right now
(yue)唔好破壞個氣氛啦
(en)Don't ruin the mood
(yue)係噉，下次
(en)Well then, next time
(yue)50年之後，我知有個睇得更加清楚嘅地方
(en)50 years later, I know a place where we can see it more clearly
(yue)我帶你哋去吖
(en)I'll take you all there
(yue)笑咩啊？
(en)What are you laughing at?
(yue)冇
(en)Nothing
(yue)咩事都冇啊
(en)Nothing at all
(yue)就噉話啦
(en)Let's just say that
(yue)大家一齊去睇
(en)Let's all go see it together
(yue)係噉，喺度講再見喇
(en)Well then, this is goodbye
(yue)跟住你有咩打算啊？
(en)What are your plans next?
(yue)我諗住繼續收集魔法
(en)I plan to continue collecting magic
(yue)我預計會用一百年左右行勻成個中央諸國
(en)I expect it will take about 100 years to travel throughout the central countries
(yue)不過，我間中會揾下你哋𠸏
(en)But I'll come find you all occasionally
(yue)精靈嘅時間觀念真係好難理解
(en)Elves' concept of time is really hard to understand
(yue)咪係囖，佢究竟可以生存幾耐呢？
(en)Right, how long can they actually live?
(yue)無論係50年定100年，對佢嚟講
(en)Whether it's 50 or 100 years, for her
(yue)或者都只係一啲微不足道嘅時間
(en)It might just be an insignificant amount of time
(yue)你話暗黑龍嘅角？
(en)You're asking about the dark dragon's horn?
(yue)我哋鋪頭冇賣呢樣嘢啝
(en)Our shop doesn't sell that
(yue)就算係暗黑龍都已經二三十年冇見過喇
(en)Even dark dragons haven't been seen for twenty or thirty years
(yue)係呀？噉就麻煩喇
(en)Is that so? That's troublesome then
(yue)召喚嗰陣要用㗎
(en)I need it for summoning
(yue)係喎，之前係魔王城執到嘅角
(en)Oh right, the horn we found at the demon king's castle
(yue)應該仲放喺欣梅爾嗰度
(en)It should still be with Himmel
(yue)硬係覺得佢散發住好邪惡嘅氣息啊
(en)I always felt it emitted an evil aura
(yue)但係應該對人冇害㗎嗬？
(en)But it shouldn't be harmful to people, right?
(yue)我唔知啊
(en)I don't know
(yue)連你都唔知呀？
(en)Even you don't know?
(yue)就嚟又到半世紀流星嘅時候
(en)It's almost time for the half-century meteor again
(yue)順便睇下佢點樣啦
(en)Let's check on him while we're at it
(yue)同上次嚟嗰陣比條街真係唔同咗好多
(en)The street has changed so much since last time we were here
(yue)我記得喺呢度附近㗎喎
(en)I remember it was around here
(yue)芙莉蓮？
(en)Frieren?
(yue)欣梅爾？
(en)Himmel?
(yue)你老咗好多啊
(en)You've aged a lot
(yue)講嘢咁過分㗎
(en)That's harsh to say
(yue)就算我而家老咗，都仲幾俊俏吖
(en)Even though I'm old now, I'm still quite handsome
(yue)已經50年冇見喇
(en)It's been 50 years since we last met
(yue)你個樣仲係同以前一模一樣
(en)You look exactly the same as before
(yue)我仲以為呢一世都唔會再見到你喇
(en)I thought I'd never see you again in this lifetime
(yue)半世紀流星呀？
(en)The half-century meteor?
(yue)好令人懷念啊
(en)It brings back memories
(yue)仲有就係關於係魔王城執到嘅嗰樣嘢
(en)Also, about that thing we found at the demon king's castle
(yue)你係咪講咁黑龍嘅角啊？
(en)Are you talking about the dark dragon's horn?
(yue)關於呢樣嘢，我從來都冇忘記過
(en)About that, I've never forgotten about it
(yue)因為佢一直喺個櫃裏面散發邪惡嘅氣息
(en)Because it's been emitting an evil aura from the cabinet
(yue)真係唔好意思
(en)I'm really sorry
(yue)其實你求其揾個倉庫
放佢入去唔理佢咪得囖
(en)Actually, you could have just found some storage and left it there
(yue)噉樣點得嗄？
(en)How could I do that?
(yue)對你嚟講，或者佢可能
只係一樣隨便寄放喺我度嘅嘢
(en)For you, it might just be something casually left with me
(yue)但係對我嚟講
(en)But for me
(yue)佢係重要嘅同伴託付畀我嘅貴重物品嚟𠿪
(en)It's a valuable item entrusted to me by an important companion
(yue)我一直都諗住將來有日可以將佢還返畀你
(en)I've always thought I could return it to you someday
(yue)明明呢樣嘢根本就一啲都唔重要
(en)Even though this thing isn't important at all
(yue)欣梅爾仲未得嗱？
(en)Himmel isn't ready yet?
(yue)你冇頭髮花時間打扮都冇意思啦
(en)You don't have hair, so there's no point spending time getting ready
(yue)光頭都有光頭嘅堅持㗎
(en)Even bald people have their principles
(yue)好喇
(en)Alright
(yue)我哋而家去睇半世紀流星喇
(en)Let's go see the half-century meteor now
(yue)你變到好有威嚴喎，海塔
(en)You've become very dignified, Heiter
(yue)因為我係聖都嘅主教啊
(en)Because I'm the bishop of the holy city
(yue)芙莉蓮，你真係一啲都冇變啊
(en)Frieren, you really haven't changed at all
(yue)唔好摸我個頭啦
(en)Don't pat my head
(yue)艾冉你個樣冇乜點變過啊
(en)Eisen, you haven't changed much
(yue)係咩？睇落冇變呀？
(en)Really? I don't look like I've changed?
(yue)不愧係矮人族啊
(en)As expected of a dwarf
(yue)係噉，你話睇得更加清嘅地方喺邊啊？
(en)So, where is this place where we can see more clearly?
(yue)嗯？
(en)Hm?
(yue)而家就出發去呀？
(en)Are we heading there now?
(yue)距離出現半世紀流星嘅時期
(en)The period for the half-century meteor
(yue)應該仲有段時間喎
(en)Should still be some time away
(yue)嗯
(en)Yes
(yue)因為要由呢度行一個禮拜過去㗎
(en)Because it takes a week to walk there from here
(yue)咩話？要行咁遠？
(en)What? We need to walk that far?
(yue)真係吖，噉折磨老人家㗎
(en)Really now, that's torturing old people
(yue)好懷念啊
(en)This brings back memories
(yue)而家噉樣行，就好似返返去嗰陣噉
(en)Walking like this now feels like back when we were returning
(yue)我哋去咗好多唔同嘅地方旅行
(en)We traveled to many different places
(yue)所有嘢都覺得好新鮮
(en)Everything felt so fresh
(yue)而且睇落好耀眼
(en)And looked so brilliant
(yue)喺我咁多美麗嘅回憶入面
(en)Among all my beautiful memories
(yue)一直都有你哋陪住我
(en)You were always there with me
(yue)我一直
(en)I always
(yue)都好期待我哋所有人可以再次聚埋一齊㗎
(en)Have been looking forward to all of us gathering together again
(yue)好多謝你啊，芙莉蓮
(en)Thank you very much, Frieren
(yue)都係多得你
(en)It's all thanks to you
(yue)我先可以體驗到最後一次開心嘅冒險
(en)That I can experience one last happy adventure
(yue)好靚啊
(en)It's so beautiful
(yue)欣梅爾佢，就嗰陣一定覺得好幸福㗎喇
(en)Himmel must have felt very happy at that moment
(yue)真係噉咩？
(en)Is that really so?
(yue)聽講嗰個女仔係欣梅爾大人嘅同伴嚟啊
(en)I heard that girl was Hero Himmel's companion
(yue)但係睇落一啲都唔傷心𠸏
(en)But she doesn't look sad at all
(yue)真係好無情啊
(en)That's really heartless
(yue)哎吔…
(en)Oh dear...
(yue)我哋兩個睇落都唔傷心喎
(en)The two of us don't look sad either
(yue)主教，你莊重啲啦
(en)Bishop, be more solemn
(yue)你真係冇人性啊！
(en)You're really inhuman!
(yue)畀人秒殺啊
(en)That was a quick defeat
(yue)因為我根本…
(en)Because I actually...
(yue)一啲都唔了解欣梅爾佢
(en)Don't understand Himmel at all
(yue)我哋只不過係…
(en)We only...
(yue)一齊旅行咗十年吒嘛
(en)Traveled together for ten years
(yue)我明明知道人類嘅壽命
(en)I knew full well that human lifespans
(yue)不嬲都好短
(en)Are always very short
(yue)點解冇諗過…
(en)Why didn't I think...
(yue)多啲去了解下佢呢？
(en)To understand him better?
(yue)唔好摸我個頭啦
(en)Don't pat my head
(yue)我都係時候要返去聖都㗎喇
(en)It's about time I return to the holy city
(yue)等我再好好睇下你哋個樣啦
(en)Let me take a good look at you all
(yue)今次係我哋最後一次見面喇
(en)This is our last time meeting
(yue)你係咪唔舒服啊？
(en)Are you feeling unwell?
(yue)飲酒飲得太痛搞到周身病痛
(en)Drinking too much has caused pain all over your body
(yue)而家報應到哩？
(en)Is karma catching up now?
(yue)如果你哋有日去開聖都，記得帶支酒
(en)If you ever visit the holy city, remember to bring some alcohol
(yue)去我墳度拜我啊
(en)To my grave to pay respects
(yue)海塔你，真係一啲都唔驚死咩？
(en)Heiter, aren't you afraid of death at all?
(yue)我哋幾個係拯救世界嘅勇者隊成員嚟𠺢嘛
(en)We are members of the hero's party that saved the world
(yue)死咗之後，唔使問一定係上天堂享福
(en)After death, we'll definitely go to heaven and enjoy blessings
(yue)我都係為咗噉樣
(en)I also did it for this reason
(yue)先會同你哋一齊去戰鬥㗎咋
(en)That's why I fought alongside you all
(yue)你個酒肉和尚
(en)You booze-loving monk
(yue)係噉，我走先喇
(en)Well then, I'll be going now
(yue)好啦，我都係時候要走喇
(en)Alright, it's time for me to go too
(yue)繼續收集魔法之類？
(en)Continue collecting magic and such?
(yue)嗯，呢個都係目的之一
(en)Yes, that's one of my goals
(yue)但係我仲想去試下多啲了解人類
(en)But I also want to try to understand humans better
(yue)乜係？
(en)What is it?
(yue)我有一件事想同你商量啊
(en)I have something I want to discuss with you
(yue)因為我係用魔法𠺢嘛
(en)Since I use magic
(yue)所以如果身邊有個強大嘅先鋒就好喇
(en)It would be good to have a strong vanguard by my side
(yue)你都係放過我啦
(en)You should just let me go
(yue)我已經年紀大到揮唔郁把斧頭喇
(en)I'm already too old to swing my axe
(yue)唔好噉嘅表情啦，芙莉蓮
(en)Don't make that expression, Frieren
(yue)人嘅一生喺歲老之後嘅時間
(en)The time in a person's life after growing old
(yue)比想象中要長嘅
(en)Is longer than you'd imagine
(yue)係呀？
(en)Is that so?
(yue)噉再見喇，艾冉
(en)Well then, goodbye, Eisen
(yue)啊，再見
(en)Ah, goodbye
(yue)（第一話：冒險結束）
(en)(Episode 1: End of the Adventure)
(yue)係頭先棵樹呀？
(en)Is that the tree from earlier?
(yue)每次嚟呢個森林都會蕩失路
(en)I get lost every time I come to this forest
(yue)呢度係邊度啊？
(en)Where is this place?
(yue)（勇者欣梅爾死之後20年）
（中央諸國）
（聖都修特拉爾郊外）
(en)(20 years after Hero Himmel's death)
(Central Nations)
(Outskirts of the Holy City of Shutteral)
(yue)請問你係咪揾緊咩啊？
(en)Excuse me, are you looking for something?
(yue)請問係咪有咩事啊？
(en)Excuse me, is something the matter?
(yue)噉𠸏，我喺度揾緊一個
叫海塔嘅人嘅屋企啊
(en)Well, I'm looking for the home of
a person called Heiter
(yue)原來你係海塔大人嘅客人呀？
(en)Oh, so you're Lord Heiter's guest?
(yue)你個酒肉和尚仲好地地喎
(en)You booze-loving monk are still alive and well
(yue)想好有型噉死
(en)Wanting to die in style
(yue)都唔係件容易嘅事嚟㗎
(en)Is not an easy thing to do
(yue)我仲買咗酒諗住放喺你個墳前面
(en)I even bought alcohol intending to place it in front of your grave
(yue)飲唔飲返杯啊？
(en)Want to have a drink?
(yue)我已經戒咗酒喇
(en)I've quit drinking
(yue)係呀？
(en)Is that so?
(yue)而家先開始改過自新
(en)Only now starting to reform yourself
(yue)我諗女神大人應該都唔會就噉原諒你
(en)I don't think the Goddess would forgive you just like that
(yue)真係唔該晒你啊
(en)Thank you very much
(yue)佢係邊個啊？
(en)Who is that?
(yue)佢個名叫做費倫
(en)His name is Fern
(yue)係南方諸國嘅戰爭留落嚟嘅孤兒
(en)He's an orphan from the wars in the southern countries
(yue)好唔似你喎
(en)That's unlike you
(yue)你不嬲都唔係嗰種會熱心助人嘅人嚟
(en)You've never been the type of person who eagerly helps others
(yue)同欣梅爾好唔同
(en)Very different from Himmel
(yue)芙莉蓮，你嚟我呢度做咩啊？
(en)Frieren, why have you come here?
(yue)我去聖都買嘢順便嚟睇你
(en)I went to the holy city to shop and came to see you on the way
(yue)因為我而家會盡量
同旅途中遇到嘅人多啲互動
(en)Because now I try to interact more
with people I meet on my journey
(yue)再加上，我仲爭海塔你好多人情
(en)Additionally, I still owe you many favors, Heiter
(yue)所以想喺你死之前還畀你
(en)So I want to repay you before you die
(yue)係噉有件事想拜託你
(en)Well, there's something I want to ask of you
(yue)嗯？
(en)Hm?
(yue)你有冇諗過收徒弟？
(en)Have you thought about taking an apprentice?
(yue)費倫佢，好有做一個魔法師嘅資質
(en)Fern has great potential to become a mage
(yue)你可唔可以帶埋佢同你一齊去旅行啊？
(en)Could you take him along on your travels?
(yue)對唔住啊，海塔
(en)I'm sorry, Heiter
(yue)我冇辦法應承你
(en)I cannot promise you that
(yue)佢會成為我嘅負累
(en)He would become my burden
(yue)你都知見習魔法師
喺實戰嘅死亡率有幾高㗎啦
(en)You know how high the death rate is
for apprentice mages in actual combat
(yue)朋友交託個細路畀我
(en)A friend entrusted this child to me
(yue)我唔打算送佢去死啊
(en)I don't intend to send him to his death
(yue)原來係噉
(en)I see
(yue)係噉，我想拜託你另一件事
(en)Well then, I want to ask you for another favor
(yue)呢本係由賢者埃維希個墓出土嘅文物
(en)This is an artifact excavated from the tomb of Sage Eveish
(yue)聽講呢本魔道書
(en)I heard this grimoire
(yue)入面記載住而家已經失傳咗
(en)Contains magic that is now lost
(yue)可以將死者復活嘅不死魔法
(en)Undeath magic that can resurrect the dead
(yue)我唔覺得呢個世界上會有呢啲噉嘅魔法囖
(en)I don't think such magic exists in this world
(yue)所以我想你幫我手解讀呢個魔道書
(en)So I want you to help me decipher this grimoire
(yue)可唔可以啊？
(en)Would that be possible?
(yue)呢啲係用圖畫做嘅暗號？
(en)Are these pictographic codes?
(yue)呢個時代嘅人真係好鍾意呢啲嘢
(en)People of this era really liked these things
(yue)只要畀五六年我都得𠸏
(en)It would take me five or six years
(yue)係噉樣呀？
(en)Is that so?
(yue)但係解讀呢啲嘢之後，你打算做咩啊？
(en)But after deciphering these things, what do you plan to do?
(yue)你之前唔係話過你唔怕死㗎咩？
(en)Didn't you say before that you weren't afraid of death?
(yue)我噉做係有兩個理由
(en)I have two reasons for doing this
(yue)第一個係
(en)The first is
(yue)我之前喺你哋面前噉講即係讕有型
(en)I said that in front of you all just to sound cool
(yue)另一個理由係我比起之前變得更加怕死
(en)The other reason is that I've become more afraid of death than before
(yue)我唔使長生不死
(en)I don't need immortality
(yue)只想長命啲
(en)I just want to live longer
(yue)長少少已經夠㗎喇
(en)Even a little longer would be enough
(yue)我想要多啲啲時間
(en)I want a bit more time
(yue)而且聖典都有寫啦
(en)And the holy scriptures also say
(yue)人要健健康康噉生活
(en)People should live healthily
(yue)長壽咪係最好嘅證明囖，芙莉蓮
(en)Longevity is the best proof of that, Frieren
(yue)你個酒肉和尚
(en)You booze-loving monk
(yue)啊，係喇
(en)Ah, that's right
(yue)喺你解讀嘅空檔時間都冇問題㗎
(en)During your breaks from deciphering, it's fine
(yue)你可唔可以幫手教下費倫佢點用魔法啊？
(en)Could you help teach Fern how to use magic?
(yue)因為我係個僧侶
(en)Because I'm a priest
(yue)所以真係唔係好識教佢
(en)So I really don't know how to teach him
(yue)如果淨係教下都得𠸏
(en)If it's just teaching, that's fine
(yue)揾到喇
(en)Found it
(yue)要揾你真係唔容易啊
(en)Finding you is really not easy
(yue)你平時都係喺森林修行嘎？
(en)Do you usually train in the forest?
(yue)原來就連芙莉蓮大人
你都覺得好難先可以揾到我呀？
(en)So even you, Lady Frieren,
find it difficult to locate me?
(yue)海塔大人成日都話
(en)Lord Heiter always says
(yue)我呢個人冇乜存在感
(en)That I lack presence
(yue)但係我覺得噉樣唔算係一件壞事
(en)But I don't think that's necessarily a bad thing
(yue)你都啱𠸏
(en)You're right
(yue)果然...
(en)Indeed...
(yue)魔力探知對佢冇乜反應咁滯
(en)Magic detection doesn't have much reaction to him
(yue)佢操控魔力嘅技術好出色
(en)His technique for controlling magic is excellent
(yue)佢咁細個
(en)He's so young
(yue)究竟用咗幾多時間去鑽研魔法啊？
(en)How much time has he spent studying magic?
(yue)海塔大人話
(en)Lord Heiter said
(yue)我打得穿山頂嗰嚿岩石
(en)If I can break through that rock on the mountaintop
(yue)就可以自己獨當一面㗎喇
(en)Then I can be independent
(yue)吓？
(en)What?
(yue)海塔都識啲嘢喎
(en)Heiter knows some things after all
(yue)嗰嚿係...
(en)That rock is...
(yue)我嘅魔力會好似噉樣散開晒
(en)My magic power scatters like this
(yue)去唔到嗰嚿石
(en)It can't reach that rock
(yue)原來係噉樣
(en)So that's how it is
(yue)係噉我應該點樣修行先至好啊？
(en)So how should I train?
(yue)喂
(en)Hey
(yue)我想問你一樣嘢先
(en)I want to ask you something first
(yue)你鍾唔鍾意魔法？
(en)Do you like magic?
(yue)我諗我都算鍾意𠸏
(en)I think I do like it
(yue)同我一模一樣啊
(en)Just like me
(yue)（第二話，不見得一定是靠魔法…）
唔係一定要靠魔法㗎
(en)(Episode 2: It Doesn't Have to be Magic...)
It doesn't necessarily have to be magic